<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Knife of Phaedrus</title>
    <link>https://lafolle.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Knife of Phaedrus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright lafolle.ca © 2020 • All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 15:26:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lafolle.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wifi</title>
      <link>https://lafolle.ca/blog/wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 15:26:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafolle.ca/blog/wifi/</guid>
      <description>Was unable to capture traffic for my wifi using airport sniff . It turns out my wifi is on channel 44 and not 1.
airport sniff 44 # works
Beacon frame -
wlan.fc.type_subtype != 0x08 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; wlan.ssid == &amp;quot;Waves in Space-5G&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; wlan.ta == e4:76:84:ce:61:0d</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impl Sha256</title>
      <link>https://lafolle.ca/blog/impl-sha256/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 08:09:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafolle.ca/blog/impl-sha256/</guid>
      <description>How does SHA256 work?
What is a hash? Given a messages M of m bits generate a data N of n bits where n &amp;lt; m. Must be collision resistant
What is cryptographic hash? h = H(x)
 Large input domain -&amp;gt; small fixed output =&amp;gt; compression Well distributed P(H(x)-i) = 1/N  Three additional properties:
 Pre-image resistant - given H(x), hard to find x. Weak collision resistance - hard to find any x such that H(x) = h Strong collision resistance - hard to find any pair such that H(x) = H(y)  How is hashing different from encryption?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Resolution</title>
      <link>https://lafolle.ca/blog/broken-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 16:58:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafolle.ca/blog/broken-resolution/</guid>
      <description>Two machines on the internet can talk to each other iff both of them know each other&amp;rsquo;s IP addresses. When we type in &amp;ldquo;google.com&amp;rdquo; in the browser, the first task of the browser is to get the IP address of &amp;ldquo;google.com&amp;rdquo; which it does by communicating with the DNS system. Once an IP address is received, the browser establishes a TCP connection to the server, does a TLS handshake, exchanges data with the server before terminating the connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dnssec</title>
      <link>https://lafolle.ca/blog/dnssec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 17:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafolle.ca/blog/dnssec/</guid>
      <description>Prelude Is DNS secure without DNSSEC??? No. All queries made by clients to recursive resolver, authoritative name servers, TLD name servers or root name servers are un-encrypted. Apart from that DNS is based on UDP protocol which is connectionless in nature such that if i have a DNS server running on my (public) machine anyone who knows the IP and port on which the server is listening for traffic, can easily send request to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lafolle.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafolle.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
I&amp;rsquo;m Karan Chaudhary. My interests span from designing and debugging distributed systems to improving developer productivity.
Currently I&amp;rsquo;m a Senior Software Engineer in Demonware.
My previous gigs were at Amazon, Fresworks and a triple of startups.
You can reach out to me here: fghjklp at the rate gmail dot com.
Thanks,
Karan</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
